BF

Braden Frazer

Frontend UX Engineer, Design Technologist

ABOUT

Frontend UX engineer with 6+ years of experience and a blended skillset between creative and technical. Passionate about fusing the gap between design and code by building design systems and component libraries. Experienced across e-commerce, marketing, templated CMS sites, and SaaS.

EXPERIENCE

Thesis

UX Engineer • April 2024 - Present

- Orchestrated the website redesign, implementing a refreshed design system and style guide sitewide.
- Generated \$1M+ in revenue through building 4-5 conversion rate optimization (CRO) A/B tests monthly.

Baylor Scott & White Health (Contract)

Front End Developer (Brand) • January 2024 - April 2024

- Ensured adherence to brand standards and the internal design system across BSWH public-facing websites.
- Analyzed and improved UI/UX across public websites after the migration from Sharepoint to Sitecore.

Dropps

UX Engineer • April 2022 - August 2023

- Systematized the design pattern library in code using Tailwind CSS and configured design tools.
- Ensured consistency between Figma and React components using Storybook.
- Backed design and 50+ A/B test initiatives with formal UX studies from Baymard and Nielsen Norman Group.
- Converted low-fidelity designs into production code for new website features as the lead frontend engineer.
- Implemented WCAG (accessibility) best practices including ARIA roles and color contrast.
- Pioneered efforts to move website code from Shopify's liquid engine over to React for greater interactivity.

Proton.ai

Frontend Engineer • May 2021 - March 2022

 Collaborated with designers to conduct user research and build features to fit client needs on an Al-powered SaaS sales platform for distributors.

Gannett I USA TODAY NETWORK

Web Developer • March 2018 - May 2021

• Built and maintained 1,000+ templated WordPress sites.

Dallas, TX

O bradenfrazer.com

& (281) 909-7514

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science • 2012 - 2017

Minored in Art and Mathematics. Graduated Cum Laude.

PROJECTS

Wonder Design System

Design System • Figma

A colorful, comic-like design system, inspired by Nintendo's hit 2023 video game 'Super Mario Wonder', and tailored to my own personal portfolio and brand.

Dropps UX Brief

UX Documentation • React, Tailwind CSS, Figma

A brief that highlights UX work I performed during my time at Dropps. It covers design system work, some components built, A/B tests ran, and other UI improvements.

Nintendle

Word Guessing Game • React, Tailwind CSS, Zustand

Nintendle is a Wordle clone with an emphasis on Nintendothemed solutions. The dictionary of solutions was curated by hand and includes a variety of Nintendo characters, themes, locations, and concepts.

Weathrr

Weather App • React, Tailwind CSS, OpenWeatherMap API

Weather conditions app built in React. The current temperature, humidity, pressure, wind speed, and conditions are pulled from OpenWeatherMap's API.

SKILLS

UI/UX

Figma	Design Syst	ems	A/B Testing	Storybook
Component Libraries		WC	AG / Accessibilit	у

Languages & Tech

HTML	CS	CSS S		SS	Tailwind CSS		JavaScript
TypeScri	TypeScript		act	RE	ST APIs	Git	

Other

Photoshop Illustrator Photography Video Editing